<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<page xmlns="http://www.partusch.de.vu">
	<meta>
		<title>Mart's Lists</title>
		<language>en</language>
		<description>A little app to create lists.</description>
		<category>program</category>
	</meta>
	<content>
		<section title="Mart's Lists are smart lists">
			<block><text>Mart's Lists lets you create and manage lists easily. It provides a convenient pad-like way to browse through your lists. Mart's Lists is designed to allow you to select and remove items efficiently. So if you use Mart's Lists to maintain your shopping list, you'll be able to check and remove items from your list right when you put them in your shopping cart.</text></block>

			<screenshot>
				<thumb width="118" height="170">../graphics/thumbs/screenshots/martslists_en_1.jpg</thumb>
				<large>../graphics/screenshots/martslists_en_1.jpg</large>
				<description>A sample list with selected entries</description>
			</screenshot>

			<screenshot>
				<thumb width="118" height="170">../graphics/thumbs/screenshots/martslists_en_2.jpg</thumb>
				<large>../graphics/screenshots/martslists_en_2.jpg</large>
				<description>Browsing through the lists</description>
			</screenshot>
			
			<block><text>But the most exciting feature of Mart's Lists is its brainpower. If you allow it to, Mart's Lists will learn automatically if an item is required regularly and in which interval. Use Mart's Lists regularly and it will remind you to buy milk or bread when it's appropriate by adding learned items to your list as suggestions with a little bright light bulb. To make your life even more comfortable Mart's Lists supports dictation of your lists on the brand new iPhone 4S! Just dictate your items separating them with "and" and after you had a chance to review and possibly correct your input Mart's Lists will add the items to your list. This works with written text too but is most convenient when dictating to the iPhone 4S!</text></block>
			<block><text>Please note that items added mistakenly should be removed from lists within 10 minutes. Only items that are at least for 10 minutes on a list are considered when learning regular suggestions.</text></block>

			<qinfo>
				<name>Mart's Lists</name>
				<features>
					<f>Convenient, pad-like interface</f>
					<f>Efficient way to check and remove items</f>
					<f>Can learn to suggest items you add regularly</f>
					<f>Designed to work well with dictation on iPhone 4S</f>
					<f>Completely accessible (VoiceOver)</f>
				</features>
			</qinfo>

			<download>
				<platform id="iphone">
					<link>
						<url>http://itunes.apple.com/en/app/marts-lists-are-smart-lists/id488513021</url>
						<text>Download in the App Store</text>
					</link>
				</platform>
			</download>
		</section>
	</content>
</page>
